A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial records, Political Files, Series 24 FA367
Rockefeller Archive Center
Nelson A. Rockefeller gubernatorial records, Political Files, Series 24
1959-1973
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich)
New York (State). Governor (1959-1973: Rockefeller)
FA367
126.23 Cubic Feet 96 standard record storage boxes, 1 legal document box.
Biographical/Historical note
Nelson A. Rockefeller served as governor of New York from January 1, 1959, to December 18, 1973. He was the first person elected to four consecutive four-year terms as a state governor.
File Plan note
Former Classification: III 15 24
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Arrangement note
There are nine subseries in this series.
Subseries 1 - Politics, 1959-1960 Subseries 2 - Politics, 1961-1962 Subseries 3 - Politics, 1963-1964 Subseries 4 - Politics, 1965, 1967 Subseries 5 - Politics, 1968-1969 Subseries 6 - Politics, 1970-1971 Subseries 7 - Politics, 1972-1973 Subseries 8 - Thank-You Letters, 1968-1972 Subseries 9 - Assorted Campaign and Political Materials, 1962-1970
Scope and Contents note
This series is composed of constituent correspondence during Nelson A. Rockefeller's four terms as governor of New York, from 1959 to 1973, and particularly the elections in 1958, 1962, 1966, and 1970. The series also reflects Rockefeller's presidential campaign efforts in 1964 and 1968. The bulk of the material is correspondence between the Governor's office and state constituents, as well as citizens from across the country and around the world.
Other Finding Aids note
Detailed finding aids for each series of this collection are available:
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Appointments Office (FA353)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Assembly and Senate Memos (FA354)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Joseph H. Boyd (FA355)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, James Cannon (FA356)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Affirmative Action (N. Lee Cook) (FA357)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Counsel's Office (FA358)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, New York State Committee to Reelect the President (FA359)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Jerry A. Danzig (FA360)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Executive Chamber (FA361)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, 55th Street (FA362)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Issue Books (FA363)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Arthur Massolo (FA364)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Hugh Morrow (FA242)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, New York Office (FA365)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Civil Service Resolutions (Charles H. Palmer) (FA366)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Press Office (FA368)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Public Relations (FA369)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Departmental Reports (FA370)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, William J. Ronan (FA371)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Speeches (FA372)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Diane Van Wie (FA373)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Ann C. Whitman, Gubernatorial (FA374)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, Gene Wyckoff (FA375)
Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial Records, New York Republican State Fund Raising Reports (FA376)
Vice-Presidents -- United States; United States; Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1966; Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1962; Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1958; Government policy; State governments -- United States; Public relations; Public policy; Presidential candidates -- United States -- History -- 20th century; New York (State); New York (N.Y.); Political science; Political campaigns -- United States; Presidential campaigns -- United States; Affirmative action programs -- New York (State); Governors -- Election -- New York (State) -- 1970; Human rights; International economic relations; International relations; International relations -- United States; Latin America; Legislation -- New York (State); Federal government -- United States; Economics; Civil service -- New York (State); Civil service; Civil defense -- United States; Civil defense; Arms control -- United States; Arms control
- 1959-1960, 1; 19 Cubic Feet
  Arrangement note
  This subseries is arranged chronologically, and then alphabetically by correspondent.
  Scope and Contents note
  This subseries, similar to the next six, contains the typical documents found in the bulk of this series, namely constituent correspondence to and from Governor Rockefeller. This subseries contains letters sent to Governor Rockefeller that were answered, those that were unanswered (labeled "no answer"), and some of the replies from 1959 to 1960. The files for L-Max are missing for both 1959 and 1960. Unique to this subseries, which documents the beginning of his 15-year tenure as governor, is the "Dinners and Luncheons" section that details functions in 1959. These folders include information on event arrangements and copies of the governor's remarks, sometimes with handwritten changes. Lastly, the distinction between "New York State Correspondence" and "New York State and Political Correspondence" is that the latter includes correspondence from outside New York State.
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (A), 1959 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Ai), 1959 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Am), 1959 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (As), 1959 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Av), 1959 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (A), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Ab), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Ac), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Ad), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Af), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Ai), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Al), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Ale), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Allen), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Aim), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Am), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (And), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Andi), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Ar), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Arn), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (As), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Av), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (B), 1959 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Be), 1959 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Bi), 1959 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Bo), 1959 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Bu), 1959 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (B), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Bae), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Bak), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Bal), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Ban), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Bar), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Barn), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Bart), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Bas), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Be), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Bec), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Bed), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Bel), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Ben), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Ber), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Bern), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Bi), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Bin), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Bis), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Bl), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Blak), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Ble), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Blo), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Bo), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Bol), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Bon), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Bor), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Bos), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Bou), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Bow), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Boy), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Br), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Bre), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Bri), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Brin), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Bro), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Brom), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Bros), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Bru), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Bu), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Bur), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Burk), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Burm), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Bus), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (But), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (C), 1959 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Ce), 1959 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Ci), 1959 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Co), 1959 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Cu), 1959 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (C), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Cal), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Cam), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Camp), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Can), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Cap), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Car), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Carl), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Carp), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Carr), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Cars), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Cas), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Cat), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Cav), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Ce), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Cer), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Ch), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Chap), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Che), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Chi), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Ci), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Cl), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 99)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Clar), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Cle), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Clem), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 102)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Cli), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 103)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Clo), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 104)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Clu), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 105)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Co), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 106)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Cof), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 107)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Coh), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 108)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Col), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 109)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Cole), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 110)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Com), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 111)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Con), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 112)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Coo), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 113)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Cor), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 114)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Corn), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 115)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Cos), 1960 (Box 2, Folder 116)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Cov), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 117)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Cow), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 118)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Cr), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 119)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Cri), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 120)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Cro), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 121)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Cru), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 122)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Cu), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 123)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Cum), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 124)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Cun), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 125)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Cur), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 126)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Cus), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 127)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Cut), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 128)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (D), 1959 (Box 3, Folder 129)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (De), 1959 (Box 3, Folder 130)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Di), 1959 (Box 3, Folder 131)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Do), 1959 (Box 3, Folder 132)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Du), 1959 (Box 3, Folder 133)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Da), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 134)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Dal), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 135)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Dam), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 136)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Dan), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 137)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Dar), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 138)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Dav), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 139)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Daw), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 140)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (De), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 141)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Dec), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 142)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Deg), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 143)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Dek), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 144)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Del), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 145)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Dem), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 146)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Der), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 147)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Di), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 148)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Dil), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 149)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Din), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 150)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Dis), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 151)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Do), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 152)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Dol), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 153)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Doo), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 154)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Dow), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 155)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Dr), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 156)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Dre), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 157)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Du), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 158)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Dul), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 159)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Dun), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 160)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Dus), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 161)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Dut), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 162)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Dun), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 163)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Dy), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 164)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (E), 1959 (Box 3, Folder 165)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Ei), 1959 (Box 3, Folder 166)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Em), 1959 (Box 3, Folder 167)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Et), 1959 (Box 3, Folder 168)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Eu), 1959 (Box 3, Folder 169)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Ear), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 170)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Eb), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 171)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Ed), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 172)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Eg), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 173)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Eh), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 174)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Ei), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 175)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (El), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 176)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Ell), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 177)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Em), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 178)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Er), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 179)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Es), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 180)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Et), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 181)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Ew), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 182)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (F), 1959 (Box 3, Folder 183)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Fe), 1959 (Box 3, Folder 184)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Fi), 1959 (Box 4, Folder 185)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Fo), 1959 (Box 4, Folder 186)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Fu), 1959 (Box 4, Folder 187)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Fa), 1960 (Box 4, Folder 188)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Fal), 1960 (Box 4, Folder 189)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Fan), 1960 (Box 4, Folder 190)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Far), 1960 (Box 4, Folder 191)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Fat), 1960 (Box 4, Folder 192)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Fav), 1960 (Box 4, Folder 193)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Fay), 1960 (Box 4, Folder 194)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Fe), 1960 (Box 4, Folder 195)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Fei), 1960 (Box 4, Folder 196)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Fen), 1960 (Box 4, Folder 197)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Fer), 1960 (Box 4, Folder 198)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Feu), 1960 (Box 4, Folder 199)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Fi), 1960 (Box 4, Folder 200)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Fin), 1960 (Box 4, Folder 201)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Fit), 1960 (Box 4, Folder 202)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Fl), 1960 (Box 4, Folder 203)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Flem), 1960 (Box 4, Folder 204)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Flet), 1960 (Box 4, Folder 205)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Flo), 1960 (Box 4, Folder 206)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Fo), 1960 (Box 4, Folder 207)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Forn), 1960 (Box 4, Folder 208)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Fou), 1960 (Box 4, Folder 209)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Fran), 1960 (Box 4, Folder 210)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Fren), 1960 (Box 4, Folder 211)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Fri), 1960 (Box 4, Folder 212)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Ful), 1960 (Box 4, Folder 213)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (G), 1959 (Box 4, Folder 214)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Ge), 1959 (Box 4, Folder 215)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Gi), 1959 (Box 4, Folder 216)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Go), 1959 (Box 4, Folder 217)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Gu), 1959 (Box 4, Folder 218)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Ga), 1960 (Box 4, Folder 219)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Gal), 1960 (Box 4, Folder 220)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Gan), 1960 (Box 4, Folder 221)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Gar), 1960 (Box 4, Folder 222)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Gart), 1960 (Box 4, Folder 223)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Gat), 1960 (Box 4, Folder 224)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Ge), 1960 (Box 4, Folder 225)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Gen), 1960 (Box 4, Folder 226)
  - New York State and Political Correspondence (Geo), 1960 (Box 4, Folder 227)